
aardio开发环境
====================================================

　　aardio（ aardio开发环境 ）专用于桌面软件快速开发，下载压缩包仅 6.x MB, 绿色软件解压即用。
开发本软件的主要目的为作者自用自娱自乐、当然也欢迎大家自由自愿免费使用， 无论个人或企业都可以免费使用本软件，使用aardio制作的软件产品不需要声明使用aardio开发。


aardio编程语言
====================================================

　　aardio是专用于桌面软件快速开发的新一代混合型编程语言,
aardio具有动态语言轻便、灵活的特性，而且又可以同时支持静态类型开发，象静态语言那样使用。

	aardio可以直接支持原生DLL，即使是外部EXE进程中的函数，也可以使用一句代码声明为普通的aardio函数对象( 原生call支持 )，
并且支持非常多的标准调用约定，例如 stdcall，cdecl，thiscall，fastcall，regparm(n)  等调用约定都可以支持。aardio虽然小，但支持的接口很丰富、
可以支持com静态动态双接口，象VBS一样原生支持com对象。

     用一个简单的代码演示一下，下面的aardio代码定义了一个结构体：
    //定义类　　
    class POINT {　　
        int x; int y; //静态类型  　 
        func = function(){　 
            //动态类型　　 
        }　 
    }
	
　　这种全新的混合编程语言开创了一种全新的编程方式，也因为这种语言特性，aardio可以非常方便的嵌入各种第三方语言，目前aardio可以嵌入汇编机器码，C语言，Java，PHP，C#，Python，Javascript，VBScript......等等数量众多的第三方编程语言，方便的互调函数，并且这些调用第三方语言的功能模块都是使用aardio实现( 开放源码 )。
　　aardio可以将硬盘目录，硬盘文件一键嵌入EXE文件，将全部程序包含所有资源生成独立的绿色EXE文件，aardio制作的程序大多不需要安装程序，也不需要释放DLL运行库，可以方便的制作免安装绿色软件。
　　aardio支持多线程开发，复杂的多线程开发在aardio中变得非常简单，标准库也提供大量简化多线程开发的辅助支持库，为多线程软件开发带来很大的方便（请参考aardio范例 -> 多线程 ）。
　　aardio的标准库基本使用纯aardio源码实现，并且全部开源，标准库提供了大量的简化编程的常用函数，涉及到软件开发的方方面面，极大的简化了桌面软件开发过程。 


软件界面快速开发
====================================================

　　aardio提供web.form支持库( 开源 )，可以方便的创建web窗体加载网页创建web风格的软件界面或实现嵌入浏览器应用，网页与aardio代码可以方便的交互调用，在aardio工程向导里，就提供了 WEB UI 的模板，在aardio自带的范例中，就有一个多窗口浏览器的范例，仅仅使用了一页约300行源码就实现了一个简单的多窗口网页浏览器。
　　另外，aardio提供了web.layout支持库，封装了轻量快速的界面引擎HTMLayout，可以使用传统的HTML，CSS技术，更加方便的实现漂亮的界面，而且运行，响应速度极快，开发工具、以及论坛中也提供了大量HTMLayout的范例，教程，以及很多大家分享的漂亮的界面源码。
　　使用aardio开发传统界面也非常的方便，aardio提供可视化开发工具，可以比较方便的的通过拖拉控件创建程序。使用标准库内置并开源的plus控件可以方便的实现控件九宫格贴图、透明贴图、仅仅通过拖拉设置就可以快速制作出漂亮的界面（参考plus控件教程）。 


关于 aardio 的读音、含义
====================================================
　　
　　aardio 读音  ['ɑ:diəʊ] 寓意为土生土长的、快速开发软件的工具( 注意aardio有双重含义，即表示aardio使用的编程语言，也表示aardio的集成开发环境 )。  


aardio开发历程:
====================================================

2004年基于开源项目lua开发出LAScript，并随当时的模拟精灵推出，
当时的LAScript仍然是一种纯脚本语言，仅支持动态类型，并不支持静态类型编程，不能直接用于原生开发、不能独立编写应用程序。只能用于编写脚本（文本格式的解释执行文件）。

于2005年开始基于LAScript研发新的快手( AAU 编程语言 ) ，
始料不及的时用了非常漫长的时间，在2007年底才完成第一个版本，启动了第一个AAU程序。
当时已经感觉到这个工程太大实非一己之力可以完成，但看到初步的成果，让我近乎狂热的投入全部的时间继续开发AAU。

克服种种艰辛，于2010年终于对外发布了第一个公开测试版本，
当时的AAU还非常粗糙，BUG很多，标准库里也只有几个简单的示例，
虽然只是发布了一些简单的范例、没有做什么推广工作，但还是吸引了不少开发者，
直到2011年年底、AAU终于发布1.0正式版，AAU标准库基本成形。

1.0以后，历经数千个版本更新，到2015年更新到 v8.89 版本。
至2015年9月，正式将快手( AAU ) 改名为 aardio。
 

关于Lua:
====================================================
Lua 是一个小巧的脚本语言, 其设计目的是为了嵌入应用程序中，
从而为应用程序提供灵活的扩展和定制功能Lua并没有提供强大的库，这是由它的定位决定的。
所以Lua本身不适合作为开发独立应用程序的语言......( 引用自：百度百科 )。

Lua是基于MIT协议的开源项目，
可以免费并自由使用于商业或非商业项目, 可以免费并自由使用于开源或闭源项目。
被授权人有权利使用、复制、修改、合并、出版发行、散布、再授权及贩售软体及软体的副本。
被授权人可根据程式的需要修改授权条款为适当的内容。

注：LAScript，aardio内核非开源项目，
    MIT无传染性，大家使用aardio不受MIT协议约束。

Lua is free software distributed under the terms of the MIT license reproduced here. 
Lua may be used for any purpose, including commercial purposes, at absolutely no cost. No paperwork, no royalties, 
no GNU-like "copyleft" restrictions, either. Just download it and use it.

Lua is certified Open Source software.  
Its license is simple and liberal and is compatible with GPL. Lua is not in the public domain and PUC-Rio keeps its copyright.

The spirit of the Lua license is that you are free to use Lua for any purpose at no cost without having to ask us. 
The only requirement is that if you do use Lua, then you should give us credit by including the copyright notice somewhere in your product or its documentation. 
A nice, but optional, way to give us further credit is to include a Lua logo and a link to our site in a web page for your product.

The Lua language is entirely designed, implemented,
 and maintained by a team at PUC-Rio in Brazil. The implementation is not derived from licensed software.

Before Lua 5.0, Lua used its own license, which was very close to the zlib license and others, but not quite the same. 
Check the source distribution for the exact license text for each version before Lua 5.0. Nevertheless, 
if you wish to use those old versions, you may hereby assume that they have all been re-licensed under the MIT license as described above.

Copyright ? 1994–2012 Lua.org, PUC-Rio.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

Copyright ? 1994–2012 Lua.org, PUC-Rio.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, 
INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. 
IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, 
WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.

LuaCOM is available under the same terms and conditions as the Lua language.

Copyright (C) 1998-2005 Tecgraf, PUC-Rio
Authors: V. Almendra, R. Cerqueira, F. Mascarenhas, and others.

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
